<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Deep Learning on </title>
		<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/categories/deep-learning/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Deep Learning </description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		
  		<language>en</language>
		
		<managingEditor>Page(/categories/deep-learning) (ixiaopan)</managingEditor>
    	
  		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
		<atom:link href="/blog/categories/deep-learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Model Selection</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/model-selection/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/model-selection/</guid>
			<description>Model Complexity What is model complexity? Perhaps it mainly refers to the number of parameters that the model has. However, it does not mean that a model is complex if it has more parameters, although it is often the case. Generally, a simple model could result in underfitting, while a complex model could lead to overfitting. So, what factors affect the complexity of a model? Well, it is hard to say.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Deep Learning - Neural Networks</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dl-02-architecture/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dl-02-architecture/</guid>
			<description>Neural Networks Neural networks are simply function compositions.
 Feedforward networks  $$ y = f(g(x, \theta_g), \theta_f) $$
 Recurrent networks  $$ y_t = f(y_{t-1}, x_t, \theta) $$
Generally, you can think of neural networks as function approximation machines, where we want to find appropriate $\theta$ to make $f^{*}$ as similar as possible to the true function $f$.
In practice, there are lots of things to consider when designing a neural network.</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Data Visualisation</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dataviz/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dataviz/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualisation is one of the modules in the first semester. Though I worked with web design and UI for several years, I&amp;rsquo;d never think about them deeply. As I learned more about design principles and the use of different charts, my aesthetic sense improved greatly. Here I listed some useful resources just for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Leetcode - 102</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/leetcode-02/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/leetcode-02/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Practice! Practice! Practice!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Deep Learning - Preliminary</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dl-01-pre/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dl-01-pre/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered most of the things that we should know about machine learning, including concepts, optimization, and popular models under the hood. Yet, some advanced techniques, such as the Gaussian Process and MCMC, are not mentioned. We will talk about them later. From now on, we will move to Deep Learning. But before that, we are going to revisit some math knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Leetcode - 101</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/leetcode-01/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/leetcode-01/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Practice! Practice! Practice!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Daily SQL Practice</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/sql/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/sql/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Practice! Practice! Practice!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Interview - Software Engineer</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/interview/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/interview/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of July, I started to look for job opportunities in Data Science, Front-End, or both. The whole process is time-consuming and tedious. Now I have achieved my goal ( I mean the experience in seeking a job, I still have no offer for now ), so I am going to share my idea and recent thoughts about job seeking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Deep Learning - PyTorch</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dl-00-pytorch/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/dl-00-pytorch/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;The most popular deep learning frameworks so far are Tensorflow and PyTorch. Well, during my study, I use PyTorch more often. Recently, I am building the classic BiLSTM-CRF model using PyTorch. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit hard for me when operating matrices since it uses various advanced techniques about indexing and slicing. I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to explain these amazing functions. Therefore, I am going to write this post to revisit the most important aspects of PyTorch for future references.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
		<item>
			<title>Sorting</title>
			<link>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/sort/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid>https://ixiaopan.github.io/blog/post/sort/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Data structure and algorithms are two important courses in Computer Science. Knowing how to utilise appropriate data structures and algorithms to fit our problems can greatly decrease memory space and improve performance. Besides, the ideas behind the classical algorithms are also worth learning to strengthen our logical thinking skills. Well, this series of articles are simply quick notes to help refresh my knowledge for future reference. So let&amp;rsquo;s start from sorting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
      	
	</channel>
</rss>
